## Navid Mashinchi

nmashinchi@gmail.com | 916-330-0268 | Irvine, CA | Portfolio | LinkedIn | GitHub

# **SUMMARY:**

Data professional with 2+ years of experience within the field of data science. Currently working as a Data Scientist I at Kohl's and Adjunct Professor at the University of Denver. KDnuggets Silver Blog and Streamlit New User of the Month award winner.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Data Scientist I, Kohl's, Remote

June 2022 – Present

Currently working in the product recommendations team within the e-commerce space.

#### Supply Chain:

- Implemented a production-ready LightGBM Model using Vertex AI and BigQuery to predict inventory item arrival at the United States Port of Entries, resulting in a mean absolute error of 6 days for inferences made six months in advance of purchase order approval.
- Modularized notebook code into Python scripts and Kubeflow components by using functional programming to successfully deploy prototype model into production.
- Developed a real-time performance monitoring dashboard using Streamlit, enabling continuous tracking and assessment of the model's performance in the production environment.

#### Associate Data Scientist, Kohl's, Remote

September 2021 – June 2022

- Promoted within ten months for exceeding goals from Associate Data Scientist to Data Scientist I.
- Developed machine learning models in Python using data stored in MongoDB for the Supply Chain team to predict when inventory will arrive at particular supply chain journey segments to provide merchants and logistics teams with better information for planning purposes.
- Optimized the ML models by hyper-parameter tuning using Optuna.
- Data visualization using Seaborn and Matplotlib to better deduce results on sampled data.

#### **Adjunct Professor**, University of Denver, *Remote*

June 2022 - Present

- Currently lecture graduate students enrolled in Machine Learning.
- Provide office hours for graduate students to answer questions regarding course materials.
- Other courses taught: Database Organization and Management I.

### **EDUCATION & AWARDS**

Master's in Data Science, University of Denver, Denver, CO, USA

August 2021

• GPA: 3.92/4.00

Bachelor of Commerce, University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada

December 2015

• Specialization: Accounting

### KDnuggets Silver Blog – March Award, Award Link

April 2021

• Earned the KDnuggets Silver Blog March award for having over 9000 views for my article: "The Portfolio Guide for Data Science Beginners".

### Streamlit New User of the Month Award, Award Link

March 2021

• Earned the new user of the month award for my COVID-19 dashboard (web app) and articles that I shared.

## **SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Python, R, JavaScript.
- Data Science: Data Cleaning & Wrangling (Pandas, NumPy), Data Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Folium, Geoplot, Ggplot2), Big Data (Spark), Statistics, Hypothesis Testing, Modeling, Interpretation.
- Machine Learning: Scikit-Learn, Supervised ML, Unsupervised ML, TensorFlow, Keras.
- Databases & Others: SQL, MongoDB, Relational Algebra, ER Modeling, GitHub, Git, Streamlit, Heroku, HTML, CSS, Node.JS, Google Cloud Platform, Vertex AI, Kubeflow.